Guide to the John White Geary Business Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
John White Geary business papers
1834-1873
WA MSS S-209
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.5
(1 box)
The papers consist of business and other correspondence, notes, accounts, and other documents.
Geary, John White, 1819-1873
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Other Geary collections at the Beinecke are the John White Geary Papers (WA MSS 212), the John White Geary Mexican War Papers (WA MSS S-585), and a letter from Geary to Major General Persifor Smith (WA MSS S-218).
JOHN WHITE GEARY (1819-1873)
John White Geary (1819-1873) served in the Mexican War in the 2d Pennsylvania Infantry, became postmaster at San Francisco in 1849, and held several other public posts in San Francisco. He returned to Pennsylvania in 1852, became governor of Kansas Territory in 1856, but resigned in 1857 and went back to Pennsylvania. Geary served with the 28th Pennsylvania Regiment in the Civil War and was twice elected governor of the state, 1867-1873.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of business and other correspondence, notes, accounts, and other documents. All letters are to Geary, unless otherwise specified. Additional unsorted papers, including: autograph documents, bonds, photos of Geary, autograph notes, etc., are included in folder marked, "Miscellaneous Material," but have not been listed.
Arrangement
This collection, listed alphabetically here, is arranged chronologically.
Kansas -- Economic conditions; Geary, John White, 1819-1873; Gilman, Charles; Graham, Margaret R.; Gwinn, C. J. M.; Jones, Andrew J.; Kirkpatrick, John M.; Klotz, Robert; Mayhew, William E.; McAllister, John H.; McAllister, Richard; McMurtie, Benjamin E.; Miller, William D., fl. 1856; Mullin, Mary Margaret; O'Hern, Michael P.; Philipps, G. Jenkin; Quackenbos, N., .Mrs.; Ray, Alexander; Remington, R.; Schley, James M.; Tellander, F.; Worrell, A.; Tebbs & Ball (Leesburg, Va.)
- Adams, Theodore. ALS. Chicago, Ill., 1857 Jun 20 (Box 1)
- Barrett, James C. ALS. Johnstown, Penna., 1856 Jun 30 (Box 1)
- Besant, James H. ALS. Point of Rocks, Md. (Box 1)
- Brooks, B. W. ALS. San Francisco, Calif., 1873 Feb 1 (Box 1)
- Brown, William. ALS. N.p., 1856 Jul 16 (Box 1)
- Campbell, John W. ALS. Hopkinsville, Ky. (Box 1)
- Creigh, J. D. ALS. San Francisco, Calif., 1856 Dec 19 (Box 1)
- Daily, Lizzie. ALS. Paradise, Penna?, 1856 Jul 18 (Box 1)
- Devecmon, Thomas. ALS. Cumberland, Md. (Box 1)
- Dougherty, B. A. ALS. Cumberland, Md. (Box 1)
- Dutton, Benjamin F. ALS. Philadelphia, Penna., 1856 Jul 5 (Box 1)
- Edwards, John T. ALS. Cumberland, Md. (Box 1)
- Fields, Ada F. ALS. Hot Springs, Va.?, 1857 Jul 19 (Box 1)
- Forney, J. W. ALS. Chambersburg, Penna., 1848 Aug 14 (Box 1)
- Geary, John White
  - AL (draft) to J. T. Edwards. Baltimore, Md., 1856 Jul 18 (Box 1)
  - AL (copy) to W. E. Mayhew. Baltimore, Md., 1856 Jun 3 (Box 1)
  - 2 AL (copies) to B. E. McMurtrie. Baltimore, Md., 1856 Jun 3, 6 (Box 1)
  - ALS to T. J. Smiley. Acquia Creek, Va., 1863 Apr 4 (Box 1)
- Gilman, Charles. 3 ALS. Baltimore, Md. (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  1856 Jul 15, 22; Sep 21.
- Graham, Margaret R. 2 ALS. Frederick, Md., 1854, 1857 (Box 1)
  1854 May 2; 1857 Aug 22.
- Gwinn, C. J. M. 3 ALS. Washington, D.C., 1856 Jul-Aug (Box 1)
  1856 Jul 5; Aug 1, 5
- Hebb, H. ALS. Cumberland, Md., 1856 Aug 5 (Box 1)
- Henderson, J. K. D. ALS to William Dunkan. Cincinatti, O., 1856 Mar 25 (Box 1)
- Higgins, James. ALS. N.p., 1856 Jun 20 (Box 1)
- Jones, Andrew J. 10 ALS., 1856-1857 (Box 1)
  1856 Jun 27, 28; Jul 9, 11; Aug 11, 14; Dec 3. 1857 Aug 3, 13; Sept 6.
- Kirkpatrick, John M. 2 ALS. Pittsburgh, Pa., 1856, 1857 (Box 1)
  1856 Aug 1; 1857 Aug 17.
- Klotz, Robert. 2 ALS. Washington, D.C.; Mauch Chunk, Penna., 1848 Aug, Nov (Box 1)
  1848 Aug 11; Nov 12.
- Long, B. B. ALS. Point of Rocks, Md., 1856 Jul 19 (Box 1)
- McAllister, John H. 3 ALS., 1857 Jul-Sep (Box 1)
  1857 Jul 4, 29; Sep 17.
- McAllister, Richard. 3 ALS., 1856-57 (Box 1)
  1856 Jul 20; 1857 Jul 3, 6.
- McKowen, Samuel. ALS. New Alexandria, Pa. (Box 1)
  Concerns crops and harvesting.
- McMurtrie, Benjamin E. 3 ALS. Huntingdon, Penna., 1856 May-Aug (Box 1)
  1856 May 28, 31; Aug 6.
- Mann, Job. ALS. Washington, D.C., 1848 Aug 4 (Box 1)
- Marden, Jesse. ALS. Baltimore, Md., 1856 Jun 23 (Box 1)
- Mayhew, William E. 2 ALS. Baltimore, Md. (Box 1)
- Mellon, Thomas. ALS. Pittsburgh, Penna., 1856 Jun 25 (Box 1)
- Miller, William D. 2 ALS. Baltimore, Md. (Box 1)
  1856 Jun 21; Jul 26.
- Mullen, M. 2 ALS. Point of Rocks, Md. (Box 1)
- Nunes, Albert A. 2 ALS. Baltimore, Md. (Box 1)
- O'Grady, James. ALS. Shelburne, Vt., 1857 Aug 28 (Box 1)
- O'Hern, Michael P. 11 ALS., 1856-57 (Box 1)
  1856 Jun 23, 25; Jul 4, 7, 16, 17, 18, 22, 23; Sep 1. 1857 Sep 13.
- Orr, John M. ALS. Leesburg, Va., 1856 Jul 3 (Box 1)
- Phillipps, G. Jenkin. 5 ALS., 1856 Jun-Aug (Box 1)
  1856 Jun 19, 24; Jul 6, 19; Aug 14.
- Quackenbos, N. (Mrs.). 2 ALS., 1858 Jan, Sep (Box 1)
  1858 Jan 31; Sep 18.
- Rainey, Robert. ALS. N.p., 1845 Dec 1 (Box 1)
- Ray, Alexander. 11 ALS., 1856-57 (Box 1)
  1856 Jun 19, 23, 26; Jul 5, 21; Aug 8, 17; Sep 5. 1857 Aug 19, 21; Sep 8.
- Remington, R. 2 ALS. New York, N.Y., 1857 Sep 7, 12 (Box 1)
- Resley, H. ALS. N.p., 1856 Jul 26 (Box 1)
- Roman, J. P. ALS. N.p., 1856 Jul 13 (Box 1)
- Ruff, B. F. ALS. Blairsville, Penna.?, 1857 Sep 7 (Box 1)
- Salmon, F. ALS. San Francisco, Calif., 1858 Jan 4 (Box 1)
- Schley, James M. 2 ALS. Cumberland, Md. (Box 1)
- Seawell, J. M. ALS. San Francisco, Calif., 1857 Jul 29 (Box 1)
- Shepardson, J. K. ALS. Independence, Mo. (Box 1)
- Smith, Sidney V. ALS. San Francisco, Calif., 1858 Mar 18 (Box 1)
- Spates, Alfred. ALS. Cincinatti, O., 1856 Jun 19 (Box 1)
- Sterett, Samuel H. ALS. Harrisburg?, Penna., 1857 Jul 3 (Box 1)
- Streeter, F. B. ALS. Washington, D.C., 1856 Dec 12 (Box 1)
- Tebbs & Ball, firm, Leesburg, Va. 6 ALS., 1856-57 (Box 1)
  1856 Jun 27, 30; Jul 3, 4; Aug 4. 1857 Sep 3.
- Tellander, F. 4 ALS. Potomac Furnace, Va., 1856 Jul 2, 12, 17; Sep 6. (Box 1)
- Thomas, Stephen. ALS. Fairlie, Vt., 1857 Jul 30 (Box 1)
- Tourison, Ashton S. ALS. Germantown, Penna., 1848 Aug 22 (Box 1)
- West, N. G. ALS. N.p., 1856 Jun 23 (Box 1)
- Wilkins, Alvan. ALS. Detroit, Mich., 1857 Sep 3 (Box 1)
- Worrell, A. 2 ALS. Philadelphia, Penna., 1857 Jul, Aug (Box 1)
  1857 Jul 25; Aug 13.
- Ziegler, J. G. ALS. Harrisburg, Penna., 1856 Aug 16 (Box 1)